<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-21T16:55:21-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PoleStar Consulting Services</title><subtitle>Polestar Consulting Services offers software development and operations support.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">History Of Money</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/history-of-money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History Of Money" /><published>2023-01-21T16:55:21-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T16:55:21-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/history-of-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/history-of-money.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>Money as we know in its current paper and coins form has only existed for the last X years. However, people have existed for Y years prior to the invention of money. How did people survive before the invention of money? The answer to that question is: bartering. The bartering system worked in the following way: people specialized in different fields in the past, some were hunters, some were medicine-men, some were ironsmiths, some were wood-workers, some were farmers, and some domesticated animals. When an ironsmith needed to feed his family, he would go to the farmer and barter some item he created, let’s say a plough, for a bag of grains. Now this seems simple, but the utility of this quickly wanes out, as a plough will serve the farmer for many years, however the bag of grains would quickly be consumed by the ironsmith’s family. So, the plough would have to fetch the ironsmith many bags or grain and not just one. So, people may have pegged the value of the plough at 10 bags of grain, of which the farmer only had 5 at the time. Now if the farmer wanted to buy some hens, he would have to establish a different bartering rate with the rancher, the doctor would need to do the same with the farmer and the rancher and so on.</p>

<h1 id="bartering">Bartering</h1>
<h1 id="gold-and-silver">Gold and silver</h1>
<h1 id="paper-currencies">Paper currencies</h1>
<h1 id="fiat-currencies">Fiat currencies</h1>
<h1 id="crypto-currencies">Crypto currencies</h1>

<h1 id="risk-and-returns">Risk and Returns</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Return and risk always go hand in hand. Whether you invest in stocks, bonds, real-estate or some other capital asset, you are rewarded mainly for shouldering risk.</li>
  <li>Returns are not possible without risk. You are rewarded only for the risk you shoulder.</li>
  <li>High returns come with high risk, and safe assets almost always yield lower returns. This is because by the fundamental definition of investing - you are rewareded for taking on risk. There is no other way about it, don’t believe anyone who promises high returns with low risks - that’s a way to spot charlatans.</li>
  <li>The biggest risk of all is failing to diversify properly.</li>
  <li>The quickest way to becoming poor is to making finding the next Tesla/Google/Amazon your goal.</li>
  <li>Individual investors routinely fail to stay the course when things get tough.</li>
  <li>Due to the mathematics of compounding, spending even tiny sums of a retirement fund on a regular basis devastates the final wealth over the long haul by several orders of magnitude. Over the last 200 years, spending 1% of someone’s nest-egg annually resulted in a decrease in the final amount by a factor of eight. A 1% annual reduction in return over a 200 year period would have reduced the final amount from $23M to $3M, and a 2% reduction in annual returns would have resulted in the final amount from $23M to $4M.</li>
  <li>Returns are uncertain, but risks at least can be controlled. You can either choose: to take a risk (invest), hedge against the risk (arbitrage, diversity), delegate the risk (insure), or avoid the risk.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="types-of-risk">Types of risk</h1>
<h2 id="credit-risk">Credit risk:</h2>
<p>The possibility of losing some or all of your capital due to the debtor’s failure.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The solution to Credit/Capital risk is to lend money only to high quality borrowers (viz: Treasury bonds). This will result in lower yields as should be expected.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="interest-rate-risk">Interest rate risk:</h2>
<p>The possibility that interest-rates rise after you have loaned the money, resulting in your bond’s price falling. The possibility that the income generated by the interest on the loan is eaten up by inflation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The solution to interest-rate risk is to lend money only for short durations (viz: Treasury bills, VCSH). This will also result in lower yields.</li>
  <li>A Treasury bill is a short-term bond that is sold at a discount to its face-value. The investor in treasury bills benefits due to the discounted price at which they purchase the bill.</li>
  <li>Face value of a bond, is the value of principal repaid at the end of the term. Market value of a bond is the price an investor will receive if he sells the bond to someone else.</li>
  <li>A corrollary of this is, short-term interest-rates must be lower than long-term interest-rates. However, for most of the 19th century short-term interest rates were higher than the long-term interest rates, this was mainly because English noblemen who lended money to fund long-term bonds liked the stability they derived from knowing how much future income they would receive 30-40 years from now. They were able to rely on the long-term returns with confidence because money at the time was backed by physical assets like (mostly) gold, head of cattle etc. With the permanent abandonment of the dollar-gold peg in the 1970s, the contemporary investor now demands high interest-rates for longer-term bonds. This is because long-term bonds and annuities now risk serious damage from increase in inflation over their duration.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="inflation-rate-risk-the-possibility-of-inflation-rising-at-a-rate-higher-than-the-interest-rate-on-the-loan">Inflation rate risk: The possibility of inflation rising at a rate higher than the interest rate on the loan.</h2>

<p>In the contemporary world of fiat currencies (currencies that are not pegged to anything physical like head of cattle, gold or real-estate), interest-rate risk is synonymous with inflation risk.</p>

<h1 id="barbarians-at-the-gate">Barbarians at the gate</h1>
<p>High returns are attained by buying low and selling high. Assets sell at low prices only when there is high uncertainty (i.e.: risk). The low prices that provide high future returns are not possible without catastrophe and risk. Thus buying when prices are low is almost always a scary proposition. (E.g.: Great Depression: 1920s, Secural bear market: 1970s, Dot-Com crash: 2000s, Great Recession: 2008s, Covid19: 2022s).</p>

<p>In the grand scheme of things, turmoil is usually short-lived and provides the opportunity to generate higher returns.</p>

<p>When the barbarians are at the gates, interest rates rise and bond prices fall precipitously. When the danger passes, interest rates fall and bond prices rise.</p>

<p>Contrastingly, when credit becomes easy (barbarians are not at the gates), interest rates fall and bond prices rise. When credit becomes tight (2023), interest rates rise and bond prices fall.</p>

<p>The rules of annuity pricing mandate that, when interest rates double, the bond prices fall by half.</p>

<p>Stability and prosperity imply high asset-prices, and due to the inverse relation between yields and prices, result in low future returns. Conversely, the highest returns are attained by shouldering prudent risk when things look the bleakest.</p>

<h1 id="survivorship-bias">Survivorship bias</h1>
<p>Only the best outcomes make it into the history books; those who failed cannot be found in the annals of history. E.g.: Stocks which fared the best during the last 200 years steal all the limelight in the investing world.</p>

<p>It is highly dangerous to rely on the investment performance of the history’s most successful investors (Warren Buffet), companies (Apple/Microsoft), nations (USA) or empires (Rome) when thinking about your own future returns. History books do not contain the stories of the vanquished.</p>

<h1 id="definition-of-investing">Definition of Investing</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Investing: The curtailment of immediate spending in exchange for future income. This makes an assumption that the money saved by curtailing immediate expenses is used to purchase an asset that produces small pieces of income, that compound over time.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="definition-of-asset">Definition of Asset</h1>
<p>Money or currencies are just a convenience mechanism to store and transact wealth. True wealth only exists in productive physical assets that churn more money, like real-estate, cattle, businesses, factories etc. So, why do non-physical assets like stocks, bonds and currencies exist? Because they simplify the headaches associated with holding physical wealth.</p>

<h1 id="definition-of-risk">Definition of Risk</h1>
<p>Risk: The possibility of losing money.</p>

<h1 id="definition-of-yield">Definition of Yield</h1>
<p>Yield: The percentage of principal that is returned as reward for shouldering risk (investing), in addition to the original principal amount.
Annual Yield: The percentage of principal that is returned to the investor each year, for loaning the principal.</p>

<h1 id="definition-of-annualized-returns">Definition of Annualized Returns</h1>
<p>Annualized returns over X years = (final_value - starting_value)/(starting_value * X)</p>

<h1 id="important-questions">Important questions</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="how-much-return-should-be-paid-by-the-borrowers-of-capital-to-its-lenders">How much return should be paid by the borrowers of capital to its lenders?</h2>
<p>We should demand higher returns if the risk of not being repaid the original capital or the promised yield are high. E.g.: During wartimes, loans start to yield at higher interest-rate because the risk of default is high.</p>

<p>The interplay between a civilization’s life-cycle and interst-rates can be plotted into a U shaped curve. Interest rates are high at the beginning of the civilization’s birth, and fall as they mature and stabilize, then rise again as they begin to decay and wither.</p>

<h3 id="interest-rates-as-a-guage-of-political-stability">Interest rates as a guage of political stability</h3>
<p>Interest rates always spike when there is uncertainty due to military, political or economic instabilities.
The lowest sustained interest-rates (4%) seen in recorded history were in the Roman civilization during the first and second century AD. This sort of forms the natural lower limit for investment returns, excluding briefer periods such as the Great Depression (1920 - 1930), the 1970s, 2000s, and 2022 where the real-return was negative.</p>

<h1 id="annuities">Annuities</h1>
<p>An annuity is a loan that pays interest forever without ever repaying the principal. The holder of the annuity can pass it on from one generation to the next. This is different than Annuities sold by Mutual Insurance companies that stop paying once the purchaser of the annuity dies.</p>

<p>Annuities are bad investment vehicles in general because, the principal is never returned back, and their yields are diminished by rising inflation.</p>

<h1 id="why-interest-rates-are-everything">Why interest rates are everything?</h1>
<p>Interest rates are nothing but the rate of return on the most oldest class of assets - loans.</p>

<p>The rate of return on an investment asset rises as the risk of losing capital rises. Assets with higher risks of loss of capital must sell cheaply, or should produce high yields, so that the return on investing in such assets is higher.</p>

<h1 id="effects-of-inflation-on-assets">Effects of inflation on assets</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Cash is the worst kind of investment to hold during inflationary periods because by definition its purchasing power erodes with increasing inflation.</li>
  <li>Bonds are generally bad investments to hold during inflationary periods because by rule, the interest-rate / yield on a bond is fixed over the duration of the bond, and increasing inflation rate lowers the real yield obtained by the bond holder.</li>
  <li>Stocks generally can cope with inflation because at least some companies can afford to raise their prices in response to inflation in cost of goods and labor.</li>
  <li>Not every company can afford to raise prices inline with inflation. E.g.: Cosmetics.</li>
  <li>Real estate is a better investment during inflationary periods, because the rental income from a property can be increased inline with inflation.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="semilog-plots">Semilog plots</h1>
<p>The vertical axis in a semilog plot has ticks that represet a ten-fold increase in value with each tick.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Financiers use semilog plots over long-durations, and annualized returns to sell investments. Annualized returns are hypothetical returns because they average out the ups and downs over a long-period of time.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="rules-of-thumb">Rules of thumb</h1>
<ol>
  <li>Stocks lose value once every 3 years. Sometimes they lose a lot (E.g.: AMZN lost 65% of its value between Jan 2022 - Dec 2022).</li>
  <li>Bonds can lose upto 15% of their value in some years, usually once every 10-30 years.</li>
  <li>Iron Rule: With stocks, (1) losses are more frequent, (2) can last longer, and (3) almost alway sting a lot harder.</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="bear-markets">Bear markets</h1>
<ol>
  <li>Great Depression: 1930s</li>
  <li>Secular Bear Market: 1970s</li>
  <li>Dot-Com Crash: 2000s</li>
  <li>Great Housing Market Crash: 2008s</li>
  <li>Covid19: 2022 - Present</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction Money as we know in its current paper and coins form has only existed for the last X years. However, people have existed for Y years prior to the invention of money. How did people survive before the invention of money? The answer to that question is: bartering. The bartering system worked in the following way: people specialized in different fields in the past, some were hunters, some were medicine-men, some were ironsmiths, some were wood-workers, some were farmers, and some domesticated animals. When an ironsmith needed to feed his family, he would go to the farmer and barter some item he created, let’s say a plough, for a bag of grains. Now this seems simple, but the utility of this quickly wanes out, as a plough will serve the farmer for many years, however the bag of grains would quickly be consumed by the ironsmith’s family. So, the plough would have to fetch the ironsmith many bags or grain and not just one. So, people may have pegged the value of the plough at 10 bags of grain, of which the farmer only had 5 at the time. Now if the farmer wanted to buy some hens, he would have to establish a different bartering rate with the rancher, the doctor would need to do the same with the farmer and the rancher and so on.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Asset Pricing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/asset-pricing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asset Pricing" /><published>2023-01-21T16:40:14-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T16:40:14-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/asset-pricing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/asset-pricing.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cape-ratio">CAPE Ratio</h1>
<h1 id="historical-returns">Historical Returns</h1>
<h1 id="risk-premium">Risk premium</h1>
<h1 id="dividends-yield-and-other-forms-of-earnings">Dividends, yield and other forms of Earnings</h1>
<h1 id="earnings-growth-rates">Earnings Growth Rates</h1>
<h1 id="rate-of-return-another-name-for-discounting">Rate of return, another name for discounting</h1>
<h1 id="asset-pricing-and-discounting">Asset pricing and discounting</h1>
<h1 id="asset-pricing-and-earnings">Asset pricing and earnings</h1>
<p>Stock prices rise in proportion to the company’s earnings. A stock that is priced 3-4 times the company’s annual earnings is considered a good asset for investments. Stocks trading at 10 times the company’s earnings do not have any room for discounting, and are over-valued. Such stocks must only be purchased if one believes in the Greater fool theory, i.e.: someone else will be willing to take such stocks at a higher price from the current owner.</p>

<p>Stocks available at 3 times the company’s annual earnings may not happen again in our lifetimes, this is because with the advent of the internet and high-speed trading, such mispriced opportunities are going to be exploited before individual/small investors have a chance of discovering such mispricing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CAPE Ratio Historical Returns Risk premium Dividends, yield and other forms of Earnings Earnings Growth Rates Rate of return, another name for discounting Asset pricing and discounting Asset pricing and earnings Stock prices rise in proportion to the company’s earnings. A stock that is priced 3-4 times the company’s annual earnings is considered a good asset for investments. Stocks trading at 10 times the company’s earnings do not have any room for discounting, and are over-valued. Such stocks must only be purchased if one believes in the Greater fool theory, i.e.: someone else will be willing to take such stocks at a higher price from the current owner.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/quality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quality" /><published>2023-01-21T15:16:17-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T15:16:17-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/quality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/quality.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="peer-reviews">Peer reviews</h1>
<p>Nothing appears in high quality journals like the Lancet, the New England Journal of Medicine etc. without being vetted first by the top experts in the field, requests for multiple extensive revisions are routine. Since, in software development, the quality of code being written is the key output of developers, we must apply similar levels of rigor in properly reviewing code and design work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peer reviews Nothing appears in high quality journals like the Lancet, the New England Journal of Medicine etc. without being vetted first by the top experts in the field, requests for multiple extensive revisions are routine. Since, in software development, the quality of code being written is the key output of developers, we must apply similar levels of rigor in properly reviewing code and design work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Readability Scoring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/readability-scoring.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Readability Scoring" /><published>2023-01-21T14:03:21-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T14:03:21-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/readability-scoring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/readability-scoring.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-readability-matters">Why readability matters</h1>
<h1 id="flesch-kincaid-score">Flesch-Kincaid score</h1>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why readability matters Flesch-Kincaid score]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">State Of Financial Markets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/state-of-financial-markets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="State Of Financial Markets" /><published>2023-01-21T13:58:02-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T13:58:02-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/state-of-financial-markets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/state-of-financial-markets.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="pre-covid19-pre-2019">Pre Covid19 (pre 2019)</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="low-interest-rates">Low interest rates</h2>
<h2 id="inflation">Inflation</h2>
<h2 id="venture-capital">Venture capital</h2>
<h2 id="crypto-currencies-autonomous-driving-and-other-fads">Crypto-currencies, autonomous driving and other fads</h2>
<h2 id="investment-options-during-this-period">Investment options during this period</h2>

<h1 id="during-covid19-2020---2021">During Covid19 (2020 - 2021)</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="shutdown-and-standstill">Shutdown and standstill</h2>
<h2 id="jobs-and-livelihood">Jobs and livelihood</h2>
<h2 id="unemployment-benefits">Unemployment benefits</h2>
<h2 id="zero-interest-rates">Zero interest rates</h2>
<h2 id="economic-stimulus">Economic Stimulus</h2>
<h3 id="child-tax-credit">Child tax credit</h3>
<h2 id="investment-options-during-this-period-1">Investment options during this period</h2>
<h3 id="sit-at-home-investing">Sit at home investing</h3>
<h4 id="stocks-options-and-cryptocurrencies">Stocks, Options and Cryptocurrencies</h4>
<h3 id="real-estate">Real estate</h3>
<h4 id="home-prices-sales-rates-rental-yields">Home prices, Sales rates, Rental Yields</h4>
<h3 id="bonds-cds">Bonds, CDs</h3>
<h4 id="bond-prices-and-yields">Bond prices and yields</h4>

<h1 id="post-covid19-2022">Post Covid19 (2022)</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="inflation-cash-becomes-trash">Inflation, cash becomes trash</h2>

<h1 id="now-2023">Now (2023)</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="soft-landing">Soft landing</h2>

<h1 id="the-future-2024-and-beyond">The Future (2024 and beyond)</h1>
<hr />
<h2 id="options-and-probabilities">Options and probabilities</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pre Covid19 (pre 2019) Low interest rates Inflation Venture capital Crypto-currencies, autonomous driving and other fads Investment options during this period]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Stock Market Is Not The Economy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/the-stock-market-is-not-the-economy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Stock Market Is Not The Economy" /><published>2023-01-21T13:53:44-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T13:53:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/the-stock-market-is-not-the-economy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/the-stock-market-is-not-the-economy.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">History of Money</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/finance/2023/01/21/history-of-money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of Money" /><published>2023-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/finance/2023/01/21/history-of-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/finance/2023/01/21/history-of-money.html"><![CDATA[<p>The history of money is rather simple. Money as we know it the current paper and coins form has only existed for the last X years. However, people have existed for Y years prior to the invention of money. How did people survive before the invention of money? The answer to that question is: bartering. The bartering system worked in the following way: people specialized in different fields in the past, some were hunters, some were medicine-men, some were ironsmiths, some were wood-workers, some were farmers, and some domesticated animals. When an ironsmith needed to feed his family, he would go to the farmer and barter some item he created, let’s say a plough, for a bag of grains. Now this seems simple, but the utility of this quickly wanes out, as a plough will serve the farmer for many years, however the bag of grains would quickly be consumed by the ironsmith’s family. So, the plough would have to fetch the ironsmith many bags or grain and not just one. So, people may have pegged the value of the plough at 10 bags of grain, of which the farmer only had 5 at the time. Now if the farmer wanted to buy some hens, he would have to establish a different bartering rate with the rancher, the doctor would need to do the same with the farmer and the rancher and so on.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="finance" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The history of money is rather simple. Money as we know it the current paper and coins form has only existed for the last X years. However, people have existed for Y years prior to the invention of money. How did people survive before the invention of money? The answer to that question is: bartering. The bartering system worked in the following way: people specialized in different fields in the past, some were hunters, some were medicine-men, some were ironsmiths, some were wood-workers, some were farmers, and some domesticated animals. When an ironsmith needed to feed his family, he would go to the farmer and barter some item he created, let’s say a plough, for a bag of grains. Now this seems simple, but the utility of this quickly wanes out, as a plough will serve the farmer for many years, however the bag of grains would quickly be consumed by the ironsmith’s family. So, the plough would have to fetch the ironsmith many bags or grain and not just one. So, people may have pegged the value of the plough at 10 bags of grain, of which the farmer only had 5 at the time. Now if the farmer wanted to buy some hens, he would have to establish a different bartering rate with the rancher, the doctor would need to do the same with the farmer and the rancher and so on.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2023-01-20T17:37:22-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T17:37:22-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry></feed>